Satoru Fujinuma,
(刑事)藤沼 悟｡ 殺人 および
放火殺人未遂の容疑で 逮捕する｡
you're under arrest for murder
and attemped murder resulting from arson.
(悟)あっ｡
Him!
《あいつだ》
It can't end here.
《終われない》
《俺には まだ…》
There's something...
I still have to do.
《やらなきゃならないことがある》
Hey.
(刑事)おい｡
Go back...
《戻れ》
Go back!
《戻れよ》
Just once more!
《もう一度だけ… 頼む》
Please!
《頼む！》
Go back!
戻れー!!
I'm glad I mustered
the courage and came here.
(雛月)勇気 出して 来てよかった｡
(悟)うん…｡
うん？
I'm really...
(悟)本当に… よかった｡
glad.
Are you stupid?
バカなの？
うん…｡
Yeah.
Satoru!
≪(ケンヤ)悟！
≪(オサム)雛月！
Hinazuki!
Hey there!
(カズ)おっす！
I finished what I had to do early.
(ケンヤ)
用事 早く済んだから 来たよ｡
Sorry we're late.
(ヒロミ)遅くなって ごめんね｡
(ケンヤ)邪魔だったかな？
そんなことないよ｡ なっ？ 雛月｡
Are we in the way?
Of course not!
- Right, Hinazuki?
- Right.
I have to pull it off.
(雛月)うん｡
《成し遂げるんだ》
Satoru is a gentleman!
This time for sure.
《今度こそ… 今回こそ…》
Definitely this time.
Doesn't have to be graceful,
《独りぼっちでも ぶざまでも
悔いのないように…》
but I can't have any regrets.
Because if I fail,
I'm not getting another chance.
《失敗すれば
次のチャンスはない》
This is my final Revival.
《これが 最後のリバイバルだ》
ERASED
I'm starving.
(カズ)なまら 腹 減ったわ｡
(ヒロミ)何か食べる？
Wanna get a bite?
(オサム)お金 ないべさ｡
I don't have any money.
I just got my allowance.
俺 小遣い もらってきたんだ｡
みんなで お好み焼き 食べない？
Why don't we have
okonomiyaki on me?
- Yeah!
- Nice one, Satoru!
(オサム)おーっ！
(カズ)ナイス 悟！
All right!
やった！ フフフッ｡
(ケンヤ)
By the way, Satoru...
そういや 悟➡
Did you read that book I lent you
the week before last?
先々週ぐらいに貸した本 読んだ？
うん？
Poe's "The Switched Man."
(ケンヤ)
ポーの｢入れ替わった男｣ってやつ｡
Sorry. I haven't read it yet.
あっ ごめん｡ まだ 読んでない｡
I don't remember that.
《覚えてない…18年前に借りた本のことなんて》
A book he lent me 18 years ago...
The story's really interesting.
面白いからさ
帰ったら 読んでみてよ｡
Read it when you get home.
I'm back!
≪ただいま！
(佐知子)おかえり 悟｡➡
Welcome home, Satoru.
Hold on, dinner will be ready in a minute.
もうすぐ ご飯できるから
ちょっと待っててね｡
What's wrong, Satoru?
Don't just stand there...
(佐知子)なした？ 悟｡
突っ立ってないで…｡
Did you have a fight with Kayo?
加代ちゃんと
ケンカでもしたかい？
No. I'm fine.
いや… 大丈夫｡
I see.
そっか｡
じゃあ 食べるべ｡
Okay, let's eat.
Sorry, Mom. Remember this.
お母さん ごめん｡
覚えておいて｡
The fact is, you can go to Ueno
without changing trains.
ホントはさ
上野には 電車一本で行けるんだ｡
What's that supposed to mean?
何じゃ そりゃ｡
February 29th, 1988
February 29th, 1988.
《昭和63年 ２月29日》
《雛月加代が連続誘拐殺人事件の 最初の被害者となる前日》
The day before Kayo Hinazuki becomes
the first victim of a kidnapping serial killer.
It's the third time I've met this day.
《この日を迎えるのは 三度目だ》
Satoru's got guts!
(ヒロミ)わあ 悟君 大胆！
That's what he said last time,
albeit a day early now.
《一日早く
前回と同じ せりふ 言ってらぁ》
Ice Hockey Club
1988 National Champions
I'm throwing caution
to the wind this time.
《今回は なりふり構わない》
Kenya...
ケンヤ あの… ごめん｡
Um, sorry.
I guess I lost the book you lent me.
借りた本
なくしちゃったみたいなんだ｡
Satoru, can I talk to you out in the hall?
(ケンヤ)悟｡
ちょっと 教室 出て 話さない？
Don't worry about the book.
えっ？
(ケンヤ)本のことなら気にしなくていいよ｡
It never existed.
そんな本は ないんだ｡
Satoru, let me say this first.
(ケンヤ)悟｡ 先に言っとく｡➡
Recently... How can I put it?
ここんとこ 何ていうか
本気の お前が見えてさ｡➡
I've seen you being serious...
and it makes me happy.
俺 うれしいと思ってる｡
Before, you used to pretend,
以前の悟は 他人に まったく関心ないくせに
あるふり してたろ？
even though you didn't care
at all about other people.
You did the best you could then,
in your own right...
それは それで
一生懸命だったと思うけど➡
but I like you better now.
俺はさ 今の悟が好きだ｡
Except I want an answer
to this nagging suspicion I have.
でも 俺は 自分の中に湧いた
疑問の答えが欲しい｡
Satoru...
悟｡ お前は 誰？
who are you?
It's like you've become another person.
俺にはさ 悟が別人になった…➡ いや
別の人格が加わったみたいに 見えたんだ｡
Or more like, another
personality has been added.
I realized you'd changed the day
I saw you looking at Hinazuki.
俺が 悟の変化に気付いたのは
悟が 雛月のことを見てた日だ｡
I'd noticed Hinazuki's cuts
and bruises a long time ago.
雛月の傷に
俺は ずっと前から気付いてた｡➡
But I couldn't do anything.
だけど 何も できなかった｡➡
I always just...
俺は いつも
こうして 人のこと 引いて見てる｡
looked on from a distance.
And yet you addressed the issue
right in front of my eyes.
(ケンヤ)なのに その俺の目の前で
お前は 踏み込んでいった｡
It was like a will that said,
俺には まるでこうやるんだっていう意思が 悟に入りこんで
"This is what you're gonna do"
had possessed your body
and put me to shame too.
俺を 叱ったように思えたんだ｡
Satoru, who the hell are you?
悟｡ お前は何者なんだ？
I...
俺は…
I'm...
《俺は…》
...a superhero.
正義の味方｡
Or, I want to be.
…になりたい人｡
プッ｡ ハハハッ！
You're Satoru after all.
やっぱ お前 悟だ｡
Kenya...
ケンヤ
雛月は 殺される｡
Hinazuki is going to be murdered.
I saw where she's physically abused.
虐待の現場を見たんだ｡
I swear I'll stop it next time.
次は… 絶対に止めてやる｡
Satoru, you don't become a superhero
after achieving results.
悟｡
正義の味方ってさ➡
結果が出たから
なれるってもんじゃないよ｡
You already are one.
お前は もう なってる｡
Let me help you.
協力させてよ｡
俺も なりたいからさ➡
I want to become one, too.
A superhero.
正義の味方｡
I thought you hated Hinazuki.
(ケンヤ)悟は 雛月のこと
嫌いなんだと思ってたよ｡➡
Like how people have an aversion
to others similar to themselves.
同族嫌悪っていうかさ｡
Yeah. I did hate her.
うん｡ 嫌いだったよ｡
でも 逆に 引かれるとこもあった｡
But I was also attracted
to something about her.
(ケンヤ)
ああ…｡ 何となく分かるよ｡
I kind of get it.
あっ…｡
(児童たち)フフフッ｡
Satoru, Kenya...
(八代)悟｡ ケンヤ｡
バケツ持って 廊下｡
Stand in the hallway with those buckets.
≪(児童たちの笑い声)
Superheroes often get
the short end of the stick.
正義の味方って
貧乏くじ 引くんだな｡
Tell me about it.
《知ってた》
I need to make a stop.
ちょっと 寄る所あるんだ｡
Hiromi, Kenya and Hinazuki, will you
wait for me at the children's center?
ヒロミ｡ ケンヤ｡
雛月と 児童館で待っててくれる？
- Sure.
- Okay.
(ヒロミ)うん｡
(ケンヤ)ＯＫ｡
MARCH
Tomorrow, March 1st,
《明日 ３月１日は 雛月を公園で
一人にさせなければ 大丈夫》
Hinazuki will be safe as long as
she isn't left alone at the park.
The problem is March 2nd,
the day of the birthday party.
《問題は ３月２日
バースデーパーティーの日だ》
I want Yuuki to have an alibi.
《ユウキさんに
アリバイが欲しい》
Yuuki, is your dad's bedroom
on the first floor?
ねえ ユウキさんの お父さんの
部屋って １階？
Y-Yeah.
(白鳥)う… うん｡
大通りの方の角｡ 何で？
Facing the main street.
Why?
Oh, I was just thinking
it was probably noisy at night.
いや 夜
うるさくないのかなとか思って｡
N-Not really...
(白鳥)そ… そうでもないけど｡
《よし｡ あと もう一つ》
All right. One more thing...
Yuuki...
ユウキさん
雛月 加代と会ってる？
Do you sometimes see Kayo Hinazuki?
W-Why?
な… 何で？
Recently, she's become
a part of our group.
最近 僕らのグループと一緒に
遊んでるから｡
R-Really?
そ… そうだったのか｡
No wonder I haven't seen her
around for several days.
どうりで
ここ何日か見ないわけだ｡
Yes! Kayo!
やったー！ 加代ちゃん
それって 最高の結果っしょ！
That's the best damn possible result!
That was the first time I'd heard Yuuki
uttering something close to a curse word.
《ユウキさんの口から
俺の前で 初めて 方言が出た》
S-See you, Satoru!
し… したっけ 悟君｡
したっけ！
See you!
I'm sure the real killer
happened to see him with Hinazuki
《あの様子だと➡ たまたま 雛月といるところを見た
真犯人に利用されたんだろ》
and decided then to use him as a patsy.
Yuuki, wait for me.
《ユウキさん 待ってて
俺が 事件を止めるから》
I'm gonna prevent the murder
from ever happening.
SHIRAKABA CHILDREN'S CENTER
Hinazuki! Kenya!
雛月！ ケンヤ！ ヒロミ？
Hiromi...
February 29th (Monday)
Satoru, we're in the gym next door!
Kenya
Over here!
(オサム)こっち こっち！
Sorry, Satoru!
(ケンヤ)あっ｡ ごめん 悟｡➡
We all came over here.
みんなで こっち来てた｡
Yeah! Get in on this, Satoru!
(カズ)おう 悟！
早く入れや！
I guess three people can't play Othello.
《そりゃ
３人で オセロはないか》
I have to be careful.
《気を付けないと…》
If I don't avoid drastic changes like this,
《まずは ３月２日まで➡ こういう急激な変化は避けないと
予想が立たなくなるぞ》
I won't be able to make predictions
through March 2nd.
(ヒロミ･カズ)おお！
I'm back!
ただいま！
(雛月)わあっ！
あっ！
(オサム)ヘヘッ｡ せーの…｡
One, two...
SATORU & HINAZUKI
HAPPY BIRTHDAY!!
Satoru! Hinazuki!
(４人)悟！ 雛月！
誕生日 おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
March 2nd 1988
March 1st was X-day
and it went just like last time.
《３月１日を 前回同様に
やり過ごしてのＸデー》
Beginning with my actions today,
I'm going to change the future.
《今日からの行動で
未来を変える》
I forgot something at school!
ちょっと 俺 学校に忘れ物｡
You're going now?
(佐知子)今 行くの!?  すぐ いるもの？
Is it something you need right away?
Bye!
(オサム)いってらっしゃ～い！
I know it looks weird,
《不自然だろうが
気にしてる場合じゃない》
but this isn't the time
to worry about that.
I'll kill you
The coup de grace!
《とどめだ》
W-What was that?!
≪(白鳥の父)な… 何だ!?➡
Hey! Who did that?!
おい！ 誰だ！
This way the police will serve
as Yuuki's alibi for tonight.
Is somebody out there?!
《これで 今晩一晩は 警察が
アリバイを証明してくれる》
Hey! Come out!
I'll get her out of the way.
《排除してやる》
If I keep her away from Hinazuki...
《あいつを
雛月の前から 排除すれば…》
If I just take you out of the picture...
《お前さえ…》
《いなくなれば！》
Keep your cool, Satoru.
冷静になれよ 悟｡
It'd be really bad if she died.
死んじゃったら まずいだろ｡
It'd be even worse if you were put away
for it, unable to help anyone.
もっと まずいのは➡ お前が
裁かれて いなくなることじゃないか？
Satoru...
(ケンヤ)悟｡
I've been following you
for the past two days.
俺 この２日くらい
お前をつけてたんだ｡
You've been desperate to save Hinazuki.
お前は雛月を助けることに 必死だった｡
That's why I thought you'd be in danger.
だから 危ないって思ったんだ｡
Thanks, Kenya.
ありがとう ケンヤ｡
It's just that I thought this was the day
Hinazuki was most at risk.
ただ どうしても 今日
雛月が 危ないって思うんだ｡
Satoru, you did something disturbing
before coming here too.
悟 ここに来る前も
何か 物騒なこと してたろ｡
What was that?
あれは 何？
T-That was to get the police over
to that house for another reason.
あ… あれは また 別で
あの家に警察を呼びたかった｡
≪(パトカーのサイレン)
I've decided. Kenya, I want your help.
決めた｡
ケンヤ 協力してほしい｡
Let's get the police to stop
that mother's abuse.
あの母親の虐待を止めるために
警察を動かそう｡
Satoru... It could cause quite a stir.
悟｡
大騒ぎになるかもしれないぞ｡
That's what I'm hoping for.
のぞむところだ｡
Have you thought
about how it'll all shake out?
ちゃんと 結末まで考えたか？
Kenya, I just came up with something.
ケンヤ
今 思い付いたんだ｡
I'll think about that now.
それは これから考えるよ｡
But I don't care
if I have to commit a crime
事件になってもいい｡
途中で見つかってもいい｡
or if I'm caught along the way.
I don't even care if they lock me up.
《俺は 裁かれたって構わない》
No matter how it ends,
どんな結末だろうと
雛月が死ぬよりはいい｡
anything is better than Hinazuki dying.
Don't do anything
that'll get you arrested, Satoru.
悟が捕まるってオチは
なしにしろよ｡
Your mom would be devastated.
母ちゃん 悲しむぞ｡
Nah.
いや うちの おふくろなら
きっと でかしたって言うと思う｡
I think my mom would say "Well done."
Actually, I can picture that.
ああ… 言いそう｡
Okay. I'm in.
ＯＫ！ やろう！
All right, I'm gonna drop Hinazuki off.
じゃあ 雛月 送ってくる｡
Go ahead!
We'll clean up here.
(カズ)行ってこい！
(ヒロミ)僕たち 片付けてるよ｡
This time I didn't forget to bring my jacket
and work gloves when I left the house.
《今回は ジャケットと軍手を
忘れずに 家を出た》
- Hinazuki...
- Fujinu...
雛月…｡
(雛月)藤沼…｡
Listen...
あのさ➡ 今から お前のこと 誘拐するけど いい？
Can I abduct you right now?
Are you stupid?
バカなの？
Yeah.
うん｡ だから
これしか思い付かなかった｡
That's why this is the only
thing I could think of.
Sure.
いいよ｡
That's what I thought you'd say.
そう言ってくれると思った｡
Episode 7
Out of Control
This is it.
ここだよ｡
A retired school bus.
もう使われていないバス｡
I hear it was the clubhouse
for Izumi Elementary's ice hockey club.
泉水小のアイスホッケー部の
部室だったんだって｡
Hi. So you two came.
(ケンヤ)よう｡ 来たか ２人とも｡
うん｡ ホントに大丈夫？
Yeah. Are you sure this is okay?
Yep. They got a new bus last year,
so this is just used for storage.
ああ｡ 去年 もう一台バス
入れてから物置になってるってさ｡
Let's open the air vents
before lighting the stove.
(ケンヤ)ストーブつける前に
換気口 開けよう｡
It's rusted out.
さびさびだ｡
Don't make it obvious
people are in here.
あまり 不自然じゃない程度にな｡
Okay.
ＯＫ｡
- Awesome...
- Wow...
すげえ…｡
(雛月)すごい…｡
This is a great hideout.
(ケンヤ)
かなり 上出来な隠れ家だ｡➡
I'd like to live here myself.
俺も ここに住みたいくらいだよ｡
Although it doesn't have a bath...
ここには 風呂ないけどね｡
Living in a big house
doesn't guarantee happiness.
でかい家に住んだから
幸せってわけでもないさ｡
Even so, I have to go home.
(ケンヤ)あーあ
それでも 帰らなくちゃ｡➡
I'll see you, Hinazuki.
じゃあな 雛月｡
I'm going home now too,
but I'll be back in the middle of the night.
俺は いったん 帰るけど
夜中に戻ってくるよ｡
I'll knock three times.
３回 ノックするから｡
Thank you, Satoru, Kenya.
ありがとう 悟 ケンヤ君｡
No need to thank me.
We're friends, Kayo.
(ケンヤ)礼は いいよ｡
友達だろ 加代ちゃん｡
I promise we'll protect you, Kayo.
俺たちが 必ず 加代を守るから｡
Ow!
"We'll protect you, Kayo." Geez.
痛っ｡ (ケンヤ)加代って お前…｡
俺だって すげえ照れくさかったよ｡
I wanted to crawl in a hole
with your line, too.
"We're friends, Kayo."
ケンヤだって 加代ちゃんって｡
Yeah. It is hard calling her that.
うん… 呼びづらい｡
ヒナの方がいいな｡
I think I'll go with "Hina" instead.
You call her Kayo, Satoru.
加代は 悟だけ呼べよ｡
Thanks.
ありがとう｡
だから 礼は いいよ｡
Like I said, there's no need for thanks.
Besides, we haven't gotten
to the hard part yet.
それに まだ こっからだろ
大変なのって｡
That's right.
そうだね｡ もし 今回の件が
表沙汰になったときはさ➡
Listen, if this goes public,
act like you don't know anything.
知らん顔してくれよ｡
ああ｡
Right.
That certainly took a long time.
ずいぶん遅かったべさ｡
Sorry.
ごめん、ちょっと寄り道して色々話してたんだ｡
We stopped somewhere along the way
and talked about this and that.
ふ～ん｡
Did you get a call from Hinazuki's mom?
もしかして 雛月の母ちゃんから 電話 来た？ いや 来ないよ｡
Nope, no calls.
Oh, that's right.
そうだ｡ 俺 あした 早いからさ
寝てていいよ｡
I'm leaving early tomorrow,
so you can go to bed.
This'll do for dinner.
ご飯は これでいいから｡
ふ～ん｡
Come in.
どうぞ｡
Were you up?
起きてたの？
寝れなかった｡
I couldn't sleep.
I don't blame you.
そうだよな…｡
腹 減んない？
Are you hungry?
This is good.
(雛月)おいしい｡
Cup noodles in the middle
of the night is good, isn't it?
夜中のカップ麺って
おいしいよね｡
It's the first time
I've had a night like this.
こんな夜中は 初めてだよ｡
まあ そっか｡
Oh. I see.
I'm planning a camping trip with Kenya
and the others for the summer.
夏にさ ケンヤたちと
キャンプの計画 立ててるんだ｡
Go with us, Kayo.
加代も 一緒に行こうよ｡
行けるかな？
I don't know if I'll be able to.
Sure you will!
行けるさ｡
Then okay.
うん｡
Wake up.
(ケンヤ)起きろ 朝だぞ｡
It's morning.
(雛月･悟)わっ！
(ケンヤ)寄ってよかったよ｡
Good thing I stopped by.
We have to get out of here
before the Izumi Elementary kids come.
泉水小のやつが登校してくる前に
出るぞ｡
March 3rd
(Thursday)
Kayo is late?
加代は 遅刻か｡
This is the afternoon broadcast.
(児童)お昼の放送です｡
皆さん 食事の前に 手を洗いましょう｡
Everyone remember to wash
your hands before lunch.
Nothing's happened yet.
今のところ 何の動きもないけど
どう思う？
What do you think?
Has Hinazuki's mother called the police?
雛月の母親 もう 通報したかな？
My guess is she hasn't looked for her yet.
まだ 捜さないんじゃないかな｡
The last time it was March 2nd,
《前回の３月２日は
21時前に 雛月が帰宅》
Hinazuki got back home before 9:00 PM.
Her mother and her mother's
boyfriend physically abused her.
《母親と その彼氏から
暴行を受ける》
They shut her up in the shed,
but she disappeared before 11:00 PM.
《23時前に 雛月は
閉じ込められた物置から 失踪》
At 12:30 AM on the 3rd,
Hinazuki's mother called Mom.
《３日 ０時30分に
雛月の母から おふくろに電話》
Just before dawn on the 3rd,
the kidnapper murdered Hinazuki.
《３日の日の出前に
犯人は 雛月を殺害》
This time there are major changes
in the actions of Hinazuki, us,
《今回は 雛月と俺たちの他にも➡ 雛月の母
犯人の行動が 大きく変わっている》
Hinazuki's mother, and the killer.
What happens after this
is uncharted territory.
《この先は 未知の領域だ》
STAFF ROOM
This is Gaku Yashiro
from Mikoto Elementary School.
(八代)美琴小学校 教員の
八代 学と申します｡➡
Yes. Please.
はい お願いします｡
(部員たちの掛け声)
Don't tell Kazu or Osamu about this.
(ケンヤ)カズとオサムには
内緒にしとけよ｡
I'm sorry for getting you
involved, Hiromi.
っていうか
ヒロミ 巻き込んで ごめんな｡
No matter what form it takes,
I'm touched that you're counting on me.
(ヒロミ)僕は どんな形でも
頼ってもらえて うれしい｡➡
And even if I went home, no one else
would be there until 8:00 PM.
どうせ 家に帰っても
８時まで 誰も いないしさ｡
Sorry to you too, Kayo.
加代も ごめんな
こんなとこ 閉じ込めて｡
Shutting you up in here...
It's okay. I've never had so much fun.
ううん｡
こんなに楽しいのは 初めて｡➡
I'm glad I mustered
the courage to come here.
勇気 出して 来てよかった｡
I'm gonna stop by your house
tomorrow morning, Kayo.
あしたの朝 加代んち 寄ってくよ｡
Her mother will have no choice
but to call the police.
母親が通報せざるを得なくするか｡
うん｡
Right.
Hey, I understand
what's going on more or less,
ねえ 話は だいたい分かったけど
結末は どうすんの？
but what happens in the end?
Don't worry. I'll take full responsibility.
心配しないで｡
俺が ちゃんと 責任 取るよ｡
Are you stupid?
(雛月)バカなの？
If I instigated it
and you guys then helped me...
私が 言い出しっぺで みんなが
協力してくれたってことなら…｡
...no one will be to blame, right? I win.
誰も おとがめないっしょ｡
はい 上がり｡
You're right.
ホントだ｡
That had been my blind spot.
《盲点だった》
On the way home, Kenya said,
《帰り道 ケンヤが 悟には
あの発想 なかっただろと言った》
"I bet you hadn't thought of that, Satoru."
"You're right," I answered
and continued,
《うんと答えた俺に こう続けた》
"Someone like that is a hero to me."
《｢俺にとってのヒーローって
そんなやつだよ｣》
Is that Satoru?
《悟… かな？》